This movement will again have a growth force,
この動きは再び成長の力を持つでしょう。
we will only take the epiblastic tissue.
私たちは上胚葉組織のみを取り上げます。
I have cells that are upwards, in divergence,
上部には発散する細胞があり、
and here, the same ones that are brought towards convergence.
そしてここには収束する同じ細胞があります。
So cells that are in an expansion dome,
つまり、拡張のドームにある細胞と、
and the others that are in an impaction dome.
もう一方は陥入のドームにある細胞です。
So I have cells that are in convexity,
つまり、凸面にある細胞と、
and cells that are placed in concavity.
凹面に配置された細胞があります。
And what do we notice again?
そして、私たちは再び何に気づくでしょうか？
That the algorithm intervenes there again.
アルゴリズムが再びそこに介入していることに。
We observe that the cells that are placed in the front part
前方に配置された細胞は、
will develop much faster than the cells that are in the back.
後方の細胞よりもはるかに速く発達することに気づきます。
And we notice that there is a fulcrum here.
そして、ここに支点があることに気づきます。
I have little growth here.
ここでの成長は少ないです。
If I add my embryo with more details on top,
もし私がより詳細な胚をその上に加えるなら、
so here I already have...
つまり、ここにはすでに...
The head, crania, cranio, caudal, which is drawn from the moment I have a creation
頭部、頭蓋、頭尾が、膜の形成から描かれています。
of a pellicle.
膜の形成から描かれています。
Below, what do I have? I have another layer of cells.
その下には何があるでしょうか？別の細胞層があります。
Yes, but within my polarity itself, I have two things happening in
はい、しかし私の極性そのものの中に、組織に2つのことが起こっています。
the tissue.
組織に2つのことが起こっています。
You can see that in the speed, the growth.
これを速度、成長で見ることができます。
It's that the ectodermal tissue has always grown faster than the tissue
それは、外胚葉組織が常に下の組織よりも速く成長してきたということです。
below.
下の組織よりも速く成長してきたということです。
It is the one that takes the information, the fastest, from the beginning, simply by
それは、単に定着によって、最初から最も速く情報を取得するものです。
nidation.
定着によって。
So the cells that are here, we will say that they are the endoblastic cells
したがって、ここにある細胞は、内胚葉細胞であり、
that will follow the movement,
動きに従うでしょうが、
but not in the same way, because they do not have the same reference,
同じようには従いません。なぜなら、それらは同じ参照、
not the same development and not the same spatio-temporal
同じ発達、同じ時空間的およびエネルギー的情報を持っていないからです。
and energetic information.
エネルギー的情報を持っていないからです。
They do not have the same geolocation information.
それらは同じ地理位置情報を持っていません。
SES, we observe that the cells that are here will develop faster.
SES、ここにある細胞はより速く発達することに気づきます。
So there is a point that we call the zero point.
したがって、ゼロ点と呼ばれる点があります。
In the wave, you see, in the wave, you have this almost immobile point, as we call it.
波の中では、ほとんど動かない点があります。
I put it in a growth process, meaning I draw it like this.
私はそれを成長のプロセスに入れます。つまり、このように描きます。
We start from the top.
上から始めます。
here, this is time, this is growth here,
ここ、これは時間、これはここでの成長、
and I tell myself, well, in the center, here, I first simply have an epiblastic tissue
そして私は思います、見てください、中央に、ここにはまず単にほぼ平らな上胚葉組織があります。
that is more or less flat.
ほぼ平らな上胚葉組織があります。
Then, very quickly, we notice that this epiblastic tissue takes the shape of an S.
その後、すぐに、このエピブラスト組織がS字型になることがわかります。
I place myself right in the center here, and I notice that the cells that are just
ここに真ん中に立って、すぐそこにある細胞が
in the axis here of the center,
ここの軸の中心に、
which are here, you see, the cells that are there, do not grow at the same speed, just there.
ここにある細胞は、同じ速度では成長していません。
And what do I see appearing, a movement like this,
そして、このような動きが現れるのが見えます。
that the upper part grows, grows like
上部がこのように成長し、
this,
このように、
and begins to grow and do that.
そして成長し始めてこれを行います。
and what is that?
そしてこれは何ですか
because here we just have
なぜなら、ここにはただ
a cut like this
このような断面があります
so here
だからここには
it's a point
点があります
as we called the point 0
0点と呼んだように
this is the part that grows
これは成長する部分です
so imagine it's a wave
波だと想像してください
Well, it's a multiplication of cells, it's an accelerated mitosis
これは細胞の増殖であり、加速された有糸分裂がこのように行われます。
that does this.
加速された有糸分裂がこのように行われます。
And what will happen?
そして何が起こるでしょうか？
Look closely, it will create, here below, a kind of tube.
よく見てください、これは下に一種の管を形成します。
kind of tube.
一種の管。
And this tube is the process of gastrulation, it's called the notochord.
そしてこの管は原腸形成の過程であり、脊索と呼ばれます。
At this stage, Hensen's node is the tip of the notochord.
この段階では、エンセン結節は脊索の先端です。
are the same. At this stage, there is a movement
同じです。この段階では、
backwards here that we call Hensen's node
後方への動きがあり、これはエンセン結節と呼ばれます。
which moves backwards, from cranio to caudal. And
これは後方に移動し、頭側から尾側へ移動します。そして
here, it's a point where it doesn't move.
ここは動かない点です。
Well, here, in this movement, you have the development of the primitive cranio-sacral axis.
そして、この動きの中で、原始的な頭仙軸の発達があります。
This means that this system is not yet neural, it is neutro-coronal.
これは、このシステムがまだ神経系ではなく、中胚葉系であることを意味します。
-coronal.
-冠状です。
This means that my notochord, the tip of my notochord, if you go and see, we will see on other diagrams, it
これは、私の脊索、私の脊索の先端が、他の図で見ると、私の頭蓋底であることを意味します。
is my skull base.
私の頭蓋底です。
This will be the future space for the development of my skull base.
これは私の頭蓋底の発達のための将来の空間となるでしょう。
And Hensen's node here at the back, that's where my sacrum will develop.
そして、ここ後方にあるヘンゼン結節は、私の仙骨が発達する場所です。
At Hensen's node.
ヘンゼン結節のレベルで。
Yes, because many people confuse Hensen's node with the closure
はい、多くの人がヘンゼン結節と後部神経管閉鎖を混同しているからです。
of the posterior neural pore.
後部神経管閉鎖。
And that has nothing to do with it!
そして、それは全く関係ありません！
But where is the adult Hensen's node?
しかし、成人のハンセン結節はどこにあるのでしょうか？
The remnant, you find it on the sacrum.
その残骸は仙骨に見られます。
You see the sacrum, like that.
仙骨がこのように見えます。
You have C1, you have S1, S2,
C1があり、S1、S2があり、
and you have the notochord that comes here.
そしてここに脊索があります。
Which comes here.
ここに来ます。
So sacrum, S1, S2, S3, S4.
したがって、仙骨、S1、S2、S3、S4。
And you have the notochord going down there.
そして、脊索がそこを下降しています。
What we call the vestige.
いわゆる痕跡です。
it's a notochord and here what do I have? I have my cul-de-sac of Douglas
それは自己の皮質であり、ここに何がありますか？ダグラス窩があります。
the zero point and Hensen's node were differentiated, initially they are together
ゼロ点とハンセン結節は分化しており、最初は一緒でした。
initially they are together, the future base of the skull is it my sacrum?
最初は一緒で、将来の頭蓋底は仙骨ですか？
no, I am together, you see, and then all of a sudden, in fact, it's not
いや、私は一緒だよ、わかる？そして突然、実際には、
that they are not
彼らが本当に分離しているわけではありません。
that they are really separated, it's a growth wave with a fixed point
それは固定点を持つ成長の波です。
which is my skull base
それが私の頭蓋底です。
system that goes down below.
下に降りていくシステム。
And that's where I have
そして、そこに私が持っているのは、
a fixed point and a mobile point.
固定点と可動点です。
And when I spoke to you this morning, I told you
そして、今朝お話ししたとき、私は言いました。
that the sacrum is a
仙骨は
mobile fulcrum and my skull
可動支点であり、私の頭蓋底は
base is a fixed
固定支点です。ブレヒシュミットは、
fulcrum. Blechschmidt,
古典的な発生学では、
we talk in classical
原腸形成のプロセスについて話します。
embryology about a process of
しかし、原腸形成という言葉は、
gastrulation. But gastrulation
両生類に由来するものです。
comes from a term that comes
ブレヒシュミットは言います。「いや、私は原腸形成について話したくない。
from amphibians.
軸方向のプロセスについて話したい」と。
Blechschmidt says no, I don't
そして、彼はこの軸方向のプロセスの確立を説明します。
I don't want to talk about gastrulation, I want to talk about an axial process.
これは断面図で、このように断面として見えます。
And he explains the establishment of this axial process.
S字型です。
This is a cut, and we see it as a cut like that, you see.
では、ゼロ点はどこにあるのでしょうか？
It's the S, you see.
あなたは下に来て、私の美しい人、ほら、そこがゼロ点です。
So where is the zero point?
アルゴリズムとは何ですか？
You come underneath, my dear, hop, there, and you are the zero point.
ドーム内の部分が、
What is the algorithm?
私の陥入ドームと比較して、はるかに速く成長すると言っています。
It tells us that the part in the expansion dome...
しかし、これはこのような空間にあると想像してください。私の胚柄はどこにありますか？
expansion compared to my impaction dome, it will grow much faster.
胚柄です。
But you imagine that it is in a space like this, where my embryonic pedicle is located.
したがって、栄養情報はここから届きます。
embryonic pedicle.
栄養情報はここから届きます。
And I make a movement like this.
そして、私はこのように動きます。
And here, inside, I have...
そして、ここに、内側に、私は持っています...
I have a tube that is forming.
私は形成されつつある管を持っています。
This is how a primitive axial process develops.
このようにして、原始的な軸方向のプロセスが発達します。
This is how, primitively, the cranio-sacral axis begins to develop.
このようにして、原始的に、頭蓋仙骨軸が発達し始めます。
The sacral point is not there yet, but it will arrive here.
仙骨の点はまだそこにはありませんが、ここに来るでしょう。
It will arrive there.
そこに来るでしょう。
I'm just showing you a dynamic, an axis.
私はあなたにダイナミクス、軸を示しているだけです。
So it goes like this.
だから、それはこのようになります。
The movement with the zero point.
ゼロ点での動き。
with this dome that comes here
ここに来るこのドームで
this is the .0 and the .0
これは.0と.0です
it's the same thing
それは同じことです
at the moment I have this wave
この波があるとき
it's the .0
それは.0です
already when I have the S
私がSを持っているときすでに
it's the .0, so yes, but not in the end
それは.0です、だからはい、しかし最終的にはそうではありません
but on the other hand it shows that the sacrum
しかし、それは仙骨が
and the occiput in the future
そして将来の頭蓋骨が
in fact it's a functional unit
実際には機能的な単位であるということを示しています
they are made
それらは作られています
of a movement
一つの動きから
so when we take this sacrum there
だから、その仙骨を取るとき
In fact, we are directly connected by this process to my skull base.
実際、私たちはこのプロセスによって頭蓋底に直接接続されています。
This kind of movement, like this, with my finger inside here.
私の指を内側に入れた、このような動きです。
And we see here a remnant of my notochord.
そして、ここに私の脊索の痕跡が見えます。
My notochord comes there.
私の脊索はそこに来ます。
It goes up to my skull base.
それは私の頭蓋底まで行きます。
I only draw the notochord, skull base,
私は脊索、頭蓋底、
all the vertebrae, up to my terminal part, at the level of the
すべての椎骨を、私の末端部分、つまり
sac.
仙骨のレベルまで描きます。
But the weight that doesn't move, it's not at the end, it was in the center, there, at the bottom.
しかし、動かない重みは端にはなく、そこ、下の中央にありました。
Yes, but you will see in the later development of the embryo,
はい、しかし、胚の後の発達でわかるでしょう、
at this stage, we can say that the anterior part of the embryo that
この段階では、ここにある胚の前部が、
is here, you see,
ほら、
so my node is there, here, and all of this is your head,
だから私の結節はここにあり、これらすべてがあなたの頭であり、
and just a small part is your trunk.
そしてほんの一部があなたの穴です。
After that, it will change shape.
その後、形が変わります。
This will develop very strongly, this less so.
これは非常に強く発達し、これはそれほどではありません。
But at this stage, it was there, right in the middle of the embryo.
しかし、この段階では、それは胚の真ん中にありました。
My point that doesn't move, and the coiling behind.
私の動かない点と、その背後にある巻きつき。
The occiput will develop here, the sacrum develops there.
後頭骨はここに、仙骨はそこに発達します。
It's in the other direction, yes, compared to the 200 as well.
それは逆方向です、はい、200に対してもそうです。
And the notochord, it's more than just starting at least.
そして、脊索は少なくともそこから始まる以上のものです。
My vertebrae, my neural tube, and there, what do I have?
私の椎骨、私の神経管、そしてそこには何がありますか？
I have my notochord.
私の脊索があります。
in the vertebrae and ultimately what will it become in the embryonic disc, what will remain is only the posus, but the axis is there from the beginning, that's why I told you
椎骨の中、そして最終的に胚性円板の中でそれはどうなるのでしょうか？
from the beginning, that's why I told you
最初から、だから私はあなたに言いました。
we treat disc problems, we have to see what happens in
椎間板の問題を治療するなら、何が起こっているかを見に行かなければなりません。
the mouth since the base
口の中、なぜなら頭蓋底は
of the skull, which is the tip of my primitive notochord, will be organized
私の原始脊索の先端であり、それは組織化されます。
organized by my occlusion, my notochord.
私の咬合、私の脊索によって組織化されます。
This is my hypophyseal cartilage.
これは私の下垂体軟骨です。
What will the hypophyseal cartilage become?
下垂体軟骨はどうなるのでしょうか？
It will become the body of the sphenoid.
それは蝶形骨体になります。
What will the parachordal cartilage that is there become?
そこにある副脊索軟骨はどうなるのでしょうか？
Parachordal, it will become the basilar part of my occipital bone.
副脊索は、私の後頭骨の基底部になります。
And there, what is that? What do we call that?
そして、これは何ですか？これは何と呼ばれますか？
The SSB.
SSB。
What is this whole story called here?
ここにあるこの一連の物語は何と呼ばれますか？
There, the base of the skull.
そこ、頭蓋底。
The difficulty is that you have to see it in three dimensions.
難しいのは、これを三次元で見なければならないことです。
At the moment I have this notochordal process taking place,
この脊索突起が定着する時、
that is to say, I have this establishment of this wave of
つまり、この波の定着があります。
mitotic construction,
有糸分裂による構築、
of this development, a little bit of an axis will appear at the level of my embryonic pedicle.
この発達によって、私の胚性茎のレベルに現れるでしょう。
a little...
少し...
of an axis that we call the primitive streak, which is an energetic field of aspiration
軸、つまり原始線条と呼ばれるエネルギー的な吸引場が
that appears
現れます。
and from this movement we will see above that my epiblast will
そして、この動きから、上の方で私のエピブラストが
transform into ectoderm but
外胚葉に変化するのを見ることができますが、
for that, through this aspiration movement, there will be a lateral traction
そのためには、この吸引の動きによって、側方への牽引が起こります。
it's this movement
それがこの動きです。
if you imagine I see the great growth of my dome part
もしあなたが想像するなら、私はドームの私の部分の大きな成長を見ています。
Here, I see a primitive streak appearing here.
ここに、原始線条が現れるのが見えます。
Here, I have this dome that will form my Hensen's node
ここに、私のヘンゼン結節を形成するこのドームがあります。
which moves backwards here, like that, you see, by growth.
それは、成長によって、このように後ろに移動します。
At the same time, in this phase of development,
同時に、この発達段階で、
the cells that are here laterally will be aspirated towards the center
ここにある細胞は、横方向に中心に向かって吸引されます。
by the growth process.
成長の過程によって。
And the epiblast that is...
そして、上胚葉は...
center will come, will form
中心が来て、形成されます
the cells here that will meet
ここで出会う細胞が
you see, will
ほら、そうなるよ
tighten like this, you see
こんな風に締め付けられるんだ、ほら
and they will become
そして彼らはなるだろう
a bottle cell, we call it
ボトルセル、と呼んでいます
bottle cells, you see, look up
ボトルセル、ほら、上を見て
it's written, bottle cells
書いてある、ボトルセル
and these will be aspirated
そしてそれは吸引されるだろう
between my tissue
私の組織の間で
that you were talking about earlier, but what
さっき話してたけど、どうなるの？
becomes of my tissue
私の組織は
below, well, between the two
下には、その間に
a space opens up
空間が開く
And in this space, there is an aspiration field
そしてこの空間には吸引場があり、
where the cells will arrive and form the primitive mesoderm.
細胞が到達し、原始中胚葉を形成します。
That is to say, at the moment I have this third cavity appearing,
つまり、この第三の腔が出現する瞬間に、
I have this notochordal process starting,
この脊索形成過程が開始され、
which will create the third tissue,
それが第三の組織を形成します。
which we call ectoderm, mesoderm, endoderm.
外胚葉、中胚葉、内胚葉と呼ばれるものです。
And that's where the mesoderm will appear.
そして、そこに中胚葉が現れるのです。
And so that's how we see that in this...
だから、このようにして、この中で、
process, you see, from my primitive streak and the displacement of my notochord, we
過程、ほら、私の原始線条と私の脊索の移動から、私たちは
see
見ます
cells appearing that begin to be aspirated towards the blood to fill the
細胞が現れ始め、血液に向かって吸引され、
intermediate tissue that will form what we call the primitive mesoblast, which
中間組織を満たし、原始中胚葉と呼ばれるものを形成します。
we call
それは、
the future mesoderm. So it is the epiblastic tissue that will
将来の中胚葉です。つまり、中胚葉を形成するのは上胚葉組織であり、
give rise to the mesoderm and
中胚葉を与え、
it is the epiblastic tissue that will give rise to the notochord. We see the wave coming
脊索を形成するのは上胚葉組織です。波が来るのが見えます。
it's really a wave in fact
それは本当に波なんだ
it's like a wave
波のようなものだ
you really have to see it like that
本当にそう見るべきだ
the tube there
そこの管は
it's created these notochords
これらのマナトコークスを生成した
and here is my Hensen's node
そしてここは私のインセンスノードだ
and there is a primitive streak that Blechschmidt does not describe
そしてそこには、ブレヒミットが記述していない原始線条がある。
at the moment
その時
when I have this process appearing
このプロセスが現れるとき
already
すでに
the mesoderm begins to form
中胚葉が形成され始めています
and it happens at the same time
そしてそれは同時に行われます
but at the same time
しかし同時に
still in this story
この物語の中でまだ
Behind here, there is a magnificent observation of
ここには、胚の対称性を分子レベルで破る節の素晴らしい観察があります。
a nodal flow that breaks the symmetry of the embryo on a molecular level.
'un flux nodal qui rompt la symétrie de l'embryon sur un plan moléculaire.
So what happens?
では、何が起こっているのでしょうか？
A few years ago, we were asking ourselves, but why is the heart on the left, why is it on the right,
ほんの数年前、私たちは疑問に思っていました。なぜ心臓は左にあるのか、なぜ右にあるのか、
why is all this inverted, etc.
なぜこれらすべてが逆になっているのか、など。
At the moment of this wave here behind, if we observe lower and lower,
この波の瞬間に、もし私たちがますます下の方を観察するならば、
we enter...
私たちは入ります...
and we see that there are small cilia moving, but that there is a fluid, which we call
そして、小さな繊毛が動いているのを見ますが、そこには液体があり、私たちはそれを呼びます
the nodal fluid,
節液、
which becomes a nodal flow. I see that wave.
それが節流になります。私はその波を見ます。
I can go up there and I can see what's happening, but quite close.
私はそこに入って、何が起こっているのかを見ることができますが、かなり近くです。
And I see that on this tissue, there are small cilia moving.
そして、この組織には小さな繊毛が動いているのが見えます。
And then, they realized that these cilia do not make a back-and-forth movement, they make a circular movement. So it turns and it always brings things from right to left.
そして、彼らはこれらの繊毛が前後運動ではなく、
from right to left. By observing, they realized that it was tilted at 60 degrees,
左へ。観察すると、それが60度傾いていることに気づきました。
degrees or 60 degrees. When it turns, when it moves away here, when it turns,
度または60度。それが回転するとき、それがここから離れるとき、それが回転するとき、
it accelerates. It does that. And so it ultimately brings
それは加速します。それはそうします。そしてそれはもたらします
a preferential flow.
最終的には優先的な流れ。
And above,
そしてその上には、
On the cells, you actually have a bit of snow falling,
細胞の上には、実際には少し雪が降っています。
which are small morphogenetic molecules.
それは小さな形態形成分子です。
So these are small vesicles that contain a lot of proteins and that are
つまり、それらは多くのタンパク質を含む小さな小胞であり、
brought at that moment by the flow from right to left.
その瞬間、右から左への流れによって運ばれます。
And these small flakes, we are in micros, they
そして、これらの小さな雪片は、マイクロの中にあり、
collide.
衝突します。
It releases a whole tissue, a whole different protein activity
それは、胚の非対称性をもたらす、まったく異なる組織、まったく異なるタンパク質活性を放出します。
that creates the asymmetry of the embryo.
différente qui rend l'asymétrie de l'embryon.
Because these are pre-morphogenetic molecules that will at some point
なぜなら、これらは形態形成前の分子であり、それが
inform the heart and the information to develop.
ある時点で心臓に情報を提供し、情報が発達するからです。
This means that at the moment I have the axial process, I have a left side, a right side,
それは、軸プロセスがある瞬間に、左側と右側があることを意味します。
an upper side and a lower side that appear.
右側、高い側と低い側が現れます。
and at the same time I have an axis
同時に軸があります
very specific
非常に特定の
and through these moments
そしてこれらの瞬間に
I have all the mesodermal tissue appearing
すべての中胚葉組織が現れます
and in addition I have a whole activity
さらに、私は活動全体を持っています
morphogenetic
形態形成の
sorry, asymmetric morphogenetic
すみません、非対称な形態形成の
that develops
それが発展する
and I have my cranio-sacral axis
そして私の頭蓋仙骨軸があります
primitive
原始的な
that arrives
到着する
well it starts between the 14th
それは14日目から始まります
and the 21st day
そして21日目
okay
わかりました